hey everyone welcome to this Tosca
automation playlist and we have been
talking about a lot of different
features which are available with Tosca
API scan in this session I am going to
talk about another interesting feature
which is called the message recorder
okay and this message recorder it
basically helps you to basically record
the traffic between your system and the
test and the backend
whenever you are running any tests or
even if you are interacting with your
browser and going to some other website
right so any kind of API calls which are
happening in your website or in your
system under test that will be captured
by this message recorder and then you
can visualize and analyze the traffic as
API messages okay
so this particular feature is available
on the top bar as you can see this is
called the record option and when you
click on this it will open the message
recorder window okay so in this message
recorder window there is a start and
stop button through which you can start
this recording session
and then there is a clear all which will
basically clear all the messages which
are already present
the configure option is basically
present to configure any proxy username
password and address you can also
decrypt the https traffic okay and then
um the export option which is basically
it will export the messages which we
have recorded into API scan okay
so let's see how this particular feature
or tool Works uh in Tosca and how you
can capture API messages as traffic
during your execution or during your
interaction with the browser okay
so now uh I'm going to start this
particular recorder so it will start
message tracing and let's start this and
you will get a stop icon right here okay
so you can stop at any time right now as
you can see there are no messages which
is being recorded right now but what
we'll do is we'll go here to Tasker
Commander and now um I will execute one
of my test cases which is for the
vehicle insurance page which is open
here okay
so let's go here and I'm going to run in
scratchbook
so any kind of interactions with any
application okay if any API messages are
being transmitted it will basically uh
record that or basically capture that
and display it here okay
let the execution complete
and then we will see what API messages
has been captured uh until now okay
so now I'm going to
come back to the recorder and you will
see that there is only one message which
has been captured that could be also the
case when you click on it okay you will
get all the information right here and
also here on different Windows okay
maybe it is not using um any particular
API and this application is mostly
front-end that's why you are only able
to see this HTTP requests right but if
you have got some backend functionality
and it is used as an API then you will
basically see that captured here okay it
will show the result it will show the
host URL content type and the process as
well right
um also
what you can do is if I come back here
right and I start interacting with this
application on my own not running any
test still
um it will be captured on the API
recorder or on the message recorder
right so if I click on this view code
it is basically a backend process okay
because it will be uh calculating or it
will be capturing some data and it will
generate this document okay now if I go
back here you will see that there is
another message now which has been
captured content type is application PDF
okay
and the result was also 200 so you can
basically analyze your traffic as API
messages and you can visualize them as
you are interacting with your
application or even if you are running
your tests in the background so it's a
very useful feature in terms of that
right
I can always go ahead and clear this all
these messages which are captured here
now let's stop this recorder okay
and now uh we have stopped the recorder
and now we can export these messages
into your API scan okay so if I click on
export you will see it will create a
folder here called Trace underscore
import and then it will capture this
message that this PDF's code dot PDF
this was the payload this was the end
point and this was that is Source okay
uh basically I should have actually
selected both the messages okay
otherwise it won't be exported so now
you can see there are two folders
created for two different messages okay
and now if I come back here I can go
ahead and clear this all this messages
which are captured here and again I can
start and I can start recording okay
so this way even if you are not aware of
some API messages which are happening in
the background for your application and
you are you know that it is using an API
you can capture this API messages in
this way and you can start capturing
those API messages right here and then
you can create your own test cases you
can start verification even if the
developers have not provided you with
the exact API messages you can still
figure out what are the API messages
using this record feature so it's quite
a useful feature if you are starting to
work on some new API development uh for
your application and you want to test
your apis then this could be a useful
feature okay
so that's all for this video hopefully
you enjoyed it and you learned something
new about API testing using Tosca
Beauty into a channel uh for more uh
similar videos we'll be talking about
lots of different topics related to
Tosca and other automation tools so
hopefully uh you can benefit from these
free videos which are available on our
Channel
also please subscribe to our Channel if
you have not already so that you get
notified about each and every new video
which we post on our channel so that's
all for now until next time keep
learning and keep enjoying our videos uh
at our Channel thank you